# THOMAS BRADLEY

Shotover Lodge, Horn Hill Road, Adderbury, Oxfordshire OX17 3EU · 07599273850 twbradley@hotmail.com - dailyhistoryfacts.com - LinkedIn - GitHub

I am a software developer looking to expand my career in the software development industry, with experience in PHP, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS with Bootstrap, Java, AWS, Docker, PHPUnit and Git through employment and personal projects, including <u>dailyhistoryfacts.com</u>, which I created to demonstrate my abilities.

I have a good work ethic and a strong desire to learn and expand my skillset with a deep interest in technology and software development – as such, I am looking for further opportunities to learn.

# **CURRENT EMPLOYMENT (2021-PRESENT)**

# **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, WEBCURL LTD**

At Webcurl I am responsible for the development and deployment of a cross-platform voice app written in JavaScript and running on Node.js, making use of the Alexa Skills Kit, Google Conversational Actions and the Jovo framework.

I have integrated well into the small development team, learning to communicate efficiently both with colleagues, and directly with clients, to ensure that deadlines and expectations are met. In addition to learning standard industry practices (such as working with Agile, and Scrum), this role has allowed me to develop my programming skills with JavaScript and PHP alongside ancillary programming tools (Docker, Git, Open Project). In addition to this, I have gained valuable experience with the Drupal framework, learning to make use of core features such as views and webforms, but also in developing custom PHP modules and working with themes in Sass to meet the professional standards of our clients.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Learn Java Course, Codecademy, September 2020
- Java Programming: Solving Problems with Software, Coursera, October 2020
- Learn PHP Course, Codecademy, May 2021
- Learn HTML Course, Codecademy, June 2021

## PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

AUG 2017 - NOV 2020

## **CUSTOMER ASSISTANT, TESCO**

I had a wide variety of responsibilities while at Tesco, many of which were customer-facing and included taking care of a range of customer needs. As a member of a large team, I learnt to work flexibly, covering other roles as required, and assisted in training new starters.

OCT 2015 - JAN 2016

## **CUSTOMER ASSISTANT, SAINSBURY'S**

I worked on checkouts during the busy Christmas period, developing my skills in communication and working under pressure.

FEB 2014 - MAY 2015

## JANITOR, ADDERBURY DAY NURSERY

I took this position while completing my GCSEs in order to garner work experience and to gain vocational skills. I learned both to work as part of a team and to prioritize tasks to a strict deadline.

2009 - 2013

## **ASSISTANT, BOOTHENWOOD LTD**

Throughout this time my parents were self-employed IT support specialists, working mainly in primary schools, providing software and hardware installations and setting up server-based networks. I assisted in this work during weekends and holidays, helping to install and test software, and set up laptops and desktops.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **JULY 2021**

# BA (HONS) ENGLISH LANGUAGE AND LITERATURE, UNIVERSITY OF READING

My experience at university enabled me to work more independently - meeting deadlines, developing analytical skills and performing abstract tasks with limited guidance. I achieved a 2-1 through consistently taking pride in my work and immersing myself in the relevant topics, despite a difficult final year with no face-to-face teaching.

#### **JULY 2018**

# A-LEVELS, WARRINER SIXTH FORM

English Language - A, English Literature - B, Psychology - C

#### **JULY 2015**

# GCSES, WARRINER SECONDARY SCHOOL

English Language - A\*, Citizenship – A, Philosophy and Ethics – A, English Literature – B, Mathematics – B, Chemistry – B, Biology – C, Physics – C, German – C, History - C

# **PROJECTS**

### **DAILYHISTORYFACTS**

This is a site written in PHP drawing from both an SQL database and querying a Wikipedia API to serve daily historical facts. It is hosted on AWS using containerization through Docker images, using an EFS to hold information. This project served as a useful introduction to OOP and the MVC model in general, alongside working in both front and backend environments, and more recently, test-driven development with PHPUnit.

## **VOICEASSISTANT APP**

This is a cross-platform app for handling requests from Google Assistant and Amazon Alexa, making use of an API on dailyhistoryfacts.com. Written in JavaScript, it makes use of Node-Red to handle the flow of a conversation.

## **ANDROID APP**

This is an app designed to replace my Google Action once deprecated. Using Kotlin, functionality is ported onto threads and coroutines and will use Google's App Actions for voice capabilities.

## **TRELLO BOT**

This is a bot that connects a Trello Kanban board to a Discord server, using a Trello API to make changes and receive notifications through a webhook, and Discord.JS to handle user commands.

## **ACTIVITIES**

I spend much of my free time working on the aforementioned projects, making use of my skills in practical settings and collaborating with friends, but I also enjoy reading (particularly history) and travelling, especially when it provides an opportunity to experience new cultures. Additionally, I have expanded my horizons through developing my language skills, using tools such as Duolingo and Babbel to teach myself Swedish at a high level, and to expand my German from school. I also enjoy using microfinancing sites such as Deki in order to provide small businesses in emerging economies with a 0% interest loan to support their growth.